Scream your last breath.
The Descent is a adventure, horror film directed by Neil Marshall.
After a personal tragedy, Sarah joins her friends on a
caving expedition in the Appalachian Mountains.
But when a rockfall traps them deep underground,
their adventure turns into a nightmare.
As they search for a way out, the group discovers they are not
alone—lurking in the darkness are savage, cave-dwelling creatures.
With rising tension and dwindling trust, the women must fight to
survive against both the predators and each other.
Sarah Carter, played by Shauna Macdonald.
Juno Kaplan, played by Natalie Mendoza.
Beth O'Brien, played by Alex Reid.
Sam Vernet, played by MyAnna Buring.
Rebecca Vernet, played by Saskia Mulder.
Holly, played by Nora-Jane Noone.
The Descent is a 2005 British horror film written and directed by Neil Marshall.
The film stars actresses Shauna Macdonald, Natalie Mendoza, Alex
Reid, Saskia Mulder, Nora-Jane Noone and MyAnna Buring.
The plot follows six women who enter an uncharted cave system and
struggle to survive against the monstrous creatures inside.
Filming took place in the United Kingdom.
Exterior scenes were filmed at Ashridge Park, Hertfordshire, and in Scotland.
Because the filmmakers considered it too dangerous and time-consuming to shoot in an actual cave, interior
scenes were filmed on sets built at Pinewood Studios near London designed by Simon Bowles.
The Descent opened in cinemas in the United Kingdom on 8 July 2005.
It premiered in the 2006 Sundance Film Festival and
released on 4 August 2006 in the United States.
The film received positive reviews with praise for the
performances, cinematography and Marshall's direction.
It was also a box-office success, grossing $57.1 million
worldwide against a £3.5 million budget.
Since its release, it has been regarded as one of
the best horror films of the 2000s.
A sequel, titled The Descent Part 2, was released in 2009.
The film explores themes of panic, darkness, mutant, expedition, cave.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.